welcome to MooMoo Math and Science in
this video let's talk about Solutions
suspensions and colloids a solution is a
mixture of two or more substances the
particles in a solution cannot be seen
light is not visible when it passes
through a solution
and it cannot be separated using a
filter
an example would be sugar and water
sugar is the solute and water is the
solvent the solute is the item being
dissolved and the solvent is what the
item is being dissolved into
this may help you remember
the difference between a solute and a
solvent think of placing the loot into a
vent to hide it so the solute goes into
the solvent
a suspension is a mixture of a fluid
with undissolved particles in it the
solid particles may be visible and will
settle over time in addition the
particles can be filtered out
light is visible when it passes through
a suspension
the solid particles are called the
internal phase and the fluid is called
the external phase
an example would be muddy water
and sand and water
the sand does not dissolve into the
water
but it's mixed into the water and over
time it will settle
a colloid is a mixture consisting of
very small insoluble particles dispersed
into a fluid
light is visible when it passes through
the colloid
you cannot use a filter to filter out
what is dispersed and the particles do
not settle over time
examples include glue
milk and fog
a colloid has a dispersed phase which
are the suspended particles and a
continuous phase which is what the
particles are suspended in
The Continuous phase can be a solid
liquid or gas
I hope that was helpful thanks for
watching and remember kindness
multiplies kindness be kind to someone
today